Hey everybody, welcome to the
content video for section 3.15,
break and continue statements. So
I keep saying this in reference to
a while loop that one of the
ways to break out of a while loop
is to use a break or continue so
we finally get to talk about it.
So break and continues are
fairly straightforward concepts.
Break will exit the loop at
any point that a break is
hit and continue skips a
single iteration of that loop.
So we will just jump to some
examples. I think that's
probably the most straightforward
way to cover this.
So break and continue.
Okay, so let's say we had, I
don't know, maybe like a for
loop, for I in range. Let's do
20. And let's say that, whoops.
let's say that once we hit the
number I don't know 10 we want
to print out every number
except 10 and we and we want to
uh not print out 10 so we could
say if i equals 10 continue
and it's as simple as that
uh and then we'll print i
okay so let's run our code
we see that the loop printed out
let's make this a little bigger zero
one two three four five six seven
eight nine and then it skipped 10 it
didn't output it and then um it continued
on and went up to 19 not including
20 of course uh so let's continue
let's do break so let's say we
wanted to do the exact same thing
actually i don't know why i'm bothering
to come up with a different example
let's just do the exact same thing
we did but this time let's say break
instead of continue so if i run
my code you can see that the code
just stops the loop stops executing
immediately after we hit the condition
that was set in there so maybe if
we had a while loop let's say age
equals five while age i don't know not
equal all right we could just say
while age because if you remember
from a previous content video all
integers all whole numbers are true um
and zero is false so if we say while
age that is basically saying while
true and so if a condition returns
true the while loop is going to
continue to run so while age will say
age plus equals one um if age equals
I don't know let's say 56 then we
will break and let's print out age so
there's a little bit of
scroll back here we can see
age starts at five and then
it gets one added to it and
it gets all the way up to
55 and then we break that
loop so the y loop does not
become an infinite loop so
yeah I think that's pretty much
everything about break and continue
they're super useful tools for if we
want to have a loop run especially
if we're like searching for something
if we want to find something in
a list or in a dictionary or something
like that and once we find it
we want the loop to stop searching
for it that's a really great way to
use break and continue but there's
really a variety of use cases for
it. So that's everything for this
content video. Thanks for watching.